Let's run away.
我們一起逃吧
Just the two of us.
就我們兩個
She seems to have turned off her phone, and we can't get a hold of her.
她好像把手機關機了，所以撥不通
Can you stay like this?
至少現在就維持這樣吧
I don't mind dying
能跟小奏在一起
if I'm with you, Kanade.
我死而無憾
Promise me.
答應我
Don't go away again.
不要再消失了
Are you feeling any discomfort?
有哪邊不舒服嗎？
Kanade? Can you hear me?
小奏？你有在聽嗎？
I knew this would happen from the start.
我明明打從一開始
I still don't think Masaki Nogi is the arsonist.
我果然還是認為野木真樹沒有縱火
Then gather the evidence to prove it.
那就只能蒐集證據
Wouldn't this car have a dashcam?
這台車有裝行車記錄器吧？
It might be this man.
是不是這個男的？
When there was a fire at Mr. Nogi's house,
就是野木律師家失火的日子
what were you doing in front of the house?
那天你在房子前的路上做什麼？
You were recorded on a dashcam.
行車記錄器拍到了你
What is this?
這是怎麼回事？
Masaki… tried to cover for me.
真樹他…
Masaki.
真樹
Yuki, did you…
祐希，你…
Hey, what's going on?
怎麼了？
You have a guest over?
有客人？
Uhh… Umm…
我…
Where do you want to go?
要去哪？
Want to go to that casual restaurant?
去家庭餐廳好不好？
Really? Can we go there?
真的？可以嗎？
But I already brushed my teeth.
我都刷牙了耶
It's okay.
沒關係喔
Yay!
太好了！
-Let's go. -Okay.
-我們走吧 -好
You asked Mr. Nogi to refer you to a new law firm?
新職場是野木律師介紹的？
This is embarrassing to talk about.
說來丟臉
But…
其實我…
I was included on the list of dismissals at my old law firm.
被先前待的事務所列為開除候補
So…
後來呢
I went to a bar association seminar, thinking I should do something.
我參加了律師公會的研討會 希望找到辦法解決
Are you Mr. Yuki Umeda?
請問你是梅田祐希律師嗎？
Do you have a minute to talk?
能借用你一點時間嗎？
Looking back, Mr. Nogi might have known that I would be there.
現在回想起來 他可能早就知道我有參加研討會
We had a talk, and he asked me a lot about Masaki.
後來他向我打聽真樹的事
He was very concerned
而且看起來
about your father.
非常在意小奏父親的事
He even knew
除此之外
about me getting fired.
他也曉得我可能會被開除的事
I've heard that you are experiencing
但我聽說梅田律師
some hardships at the moment.
你最近過得滿辛苦的
I can help you if you would like.
如果不嫌棄，我可以協助你
But after that,
可是在那之後
Mr. Nogi completely stopped contacting me.
野木律師就斷了聯繫
I tried to get in touch many times but no reply.
我主動聯絡也沒有回覆
I felt like he wasn't serious about helping me get a job.
我想說他只是嘴上說要幫我
And then…
不過…
I was fired from my law firm,
我被事務所開除後
and couldn't get hired anywhere else.
遲遲找不到下一個職場
It made me terribly anxious.
我徹底慌了
Is that why…
所以你才…
I just couldn't give up on the idea.
我實在無法放棄
So that night…
就在那天…
I went to Mr. Nogi's house.
跑去野木律師的家
Yes.
你好
Uh, pardon me for disturbing you at night.
那個，不好意思這麼晚來拜訪
My name is Umeda, and I'm a lawyer.
敝姓梅田，是一名律師
Is Mr. Nogi home?
請問野木律師在家嗎？
It's me speaking.
我就是
M-Mr. Nogi? It's me, Umeda.
是野木律師啊？我是梅田
I know this might be rude,
我知道這麼做非常失禮
but could I please speak with you, even for just a little bit?
但能不能占用一點時間談談呢？
It's about a job referral as we discussed before.
是關於之前找工作的事
I'm sorry, but I have company at the moment.
不好意思，我現在有訪客
Then, when would be better?
那請問何時有空？
I will contact you later.
我會再聯絡你
I thought he didn't want to deal with me
他當時說有訪客
so he made up a lie about having company.
本來以為他是嫌煩才說謊打發我
Of course,
我也明白
I knew that what I was doing totally lacked common sense.
自己這麼做缺乏常識
But I didn't feel like going straight home
可是我沒辦法乖乖回去
so I wandered around that area.
只好在附近閒晃
I even thought to myself
追根究柢
I was never cut out to be a lawyer to begin with.
我根本不適合當律師
My thoughts went that far back.
我甚至忍不住有這種念頭
You shouldn't say that.
才沒有那種事
You passed the bar exam, didn't you?
你明明就通過司法考試啦
I passed because
只有那時候
I was so desperate at the time.
我得奮不顧身地努力
When I was in law school, Tomo became pregnant.
唸法科大學院時小知懷了希實
So we decided to get married.
我們決定結婚
Then Tomo told me she wasn't going to take the bar exam.
小知還說不考司法考試了
She was studying so hard for it.
她明明那麼努力地念書
She did so much better than me, there was no doubt she'd pass.
她比我還優秀，肯定能一次考過
You know…
我啊
I'm not good at dealing with other people's problems.
本來就不擅長跟人爭執
Being a lawyer…
做這份工作
stresses me out so much, and it's exhausting for me.
總覺得會消磨精神，非常疲憊
But…
可是…
I had to do it for Tomo and Nozomi.
我得為了小知跟希實加油
That was my motivation.
我只能這麼激勵自己
I went to Mr. Nogi's house one more time.
後來再次前往野木律師家
You went back?
你回去了？
Yes.
對
What was I doing? People would think I'm a burglar!
我到底在幹什麼？ 這樣跟小偷沒兩樣嘛
Just when I was realizing how bad it looked…
正當我覺得自己的行為不可取時…
Fire!
失火了！
What were you doing?
你在那做什麼？
Huh?
什麼？
Hey, wait!
等等，給我站住！
It's him! He's getting away!
就是他！往那邊跑了！
Masaki.
真樹
Yuki, did you…
祐希，你…
No, Masaki.
不是的，真樹
-I… -Just go.
-我… -你快走
-But… -Hurry!
-但是… -快走！
Huh…
當時我無地自容
I even caused Masaki to suspect me of setting it.
想說連真樹都懷疑我
I felt so pathetic.
真的太丟臉了
But I ran like hell.
不過我拼了命地逃
I ran faster than I ever did in my life.
這輩子從沒跑這麼快過
As if my life depended on it.
總之只顧著不停地跑
The next day,
到了隔天
I found out on the news that Masaki had been arrested.
我在新聞上得知真樹遭逮捕
Then…
意思是…
you mean you were there by accident, and you had nothing to do with the fire?
祐希只是碰巧在場 跟這起火災毫無關係？
It wasn't me.
不是我做的
I swear to God, I didn't do it.
我敢對天發誓真的沒做
And Masaki
結果真樹他包庇了你？
Why didn't you tell anybody?
為何你不說出來？
-Not even to Tomo? -I wanted to tell her!
-連小知也瞞著？ -我也想說啊！
So many times.
有好幾次都想說出來
But at that moment,
但是後來我才知道
I found out that Mr. Nogi
野木律師他啊
had been looking for a law firm for me.
其實真的有幫我找事務所
-Tomo was so excited. -International Cultural Law Firm?
-小知聽了非常開心 -國際文化法律事務所？
That's awesome! That's great!
你真厲害！太好了！
Y-Yeah…
是啊
So you couldn't tell her at all?
所以你就開不了口？
I felt so truly sorry for Masaki
雖然我真的打從心底
this whole time, but…
覺得對不起真樹…
in this situation, even if I tell the police what happened,
但即使在這種狀況下說真話
there's nothing to back up my story.
警方也不會相信我的證詞 畢竟沒證據
I can't prove my innocence.
我無法證明自己是清白的
If I got arrested,
要是我被逮捕
what would happen to Tomo and Nozomi?
那就會把小知跟希實拖下水
I-I was terrified.
我怕到不行
But…
可是…
that's the reason…
你選擇那麼做…
Masaki has been detained now.
害真樹現在被拘留了
And in such ill health.
身體都快撐不住了
I'm sorry.
對不起
Kanade.
小奏
I'm so sorry.
真的很抱歉
It's not me you need to apologize to.
你不該對我道歉
It's all because of my weakness…
我太懦弱了
I feel pathetic.
真是沒出息
What's the matter? Why aren't you eating?
怎麼了？不吃嗎？
Mom.
媽媽
Is Dad in some kind of trouble?
爸爸是不是出事了啊？
What? Why?
胡說什麼？
No, he isn't.
才沒有呢
No matter what happens,
不論發生什麼事
I'm on Mom and Dad's side.
我都會站在爸爸跟媽媽這邊
Huh?
幹嘛講這些？
I'll protect you, Mom.
我會負責保護媽媽
Hey. Everything's fine.
就跟你說沒事啦
There's nothing to worry about.
沒什麼好擔心的
Okay?
知道了嗎？
Okay.
好
So go ahead and eat.
快吃吧…
I…
我…
I'll turn myself in.
會主動去警局作證
Mm-hmm.
好
Kanade.
小奏
What?
什麼事？
If something…
要是…
happens to me for any reason…
我有個萬一…
will you watch over Tomo and Nozomi?
小知跟希實 就拜託你照顧了，好嗎？
Don't worry.
不會有事的
But…
可是…
Yuki.
祐希
As your friend,
我是以朋友的身分
I believe what you just told me.
相信你剛才說的話
But you know,
不過啊
I'm a prosecutor.
我是檢察官
I can't just accept your words as is.
沒辦法聽信片面之詞
All I can do
我唯一能做的
is seek out the truth.
就是找出真相
To prove you are both innocent,
為了證明你們兩個是無辜的
I promise you I'll find out the truth.
我一定會揭露真相
The next morning,
隔天早上
Yuki turned himself in at Yokohama Minami Police Station.
祐希主動前往橫濱南署作證
He is not in a condition to speak then.
所以他現在還沒辦法開口說話啊
Yes, unfortunately…
對，真是遺憾
But he is making progress.
不過他的病情算是穩定
I see.
這樣啊
We're lucky he's regained consciousness from the state he was in.
光是能從那種狀態下甦醒 就已經算是很幸運了
Excuse me.
那我失陪了
So it's still impossible to interview Koichiro Nogi?
所以現在野木浩一郎無法會客？
Yes. Even though he's the only one aware of how the fire started.
是的，他是唯一瞭解失火原因的人
How about Yuki Umeda who turned himself in?
主動去警局的梅田祐希呢？
He says Masaki Nogi isn't the arsonist, he is lying to protect him.
他主張野木真樹沒有縱火 而是為了包庇自己才說謊
But Umeda himself is also denying that he did it.
然而梅田本人也否認縱火
Yes.
是的
Did you question Masaki Nogi yet?
何時要訊問野木真樹？
Not yet.
晚點就會進行
How is his health?
他身體狀況如何？
So far, there's no change.
目前病情沒有劇變
Although,
只不過
it is certain that he needs treatment.
他需要立即進行治療
I see.
我明白了
Please enter.
進去吧
It was the first time seeing him since that day.
那天之後我第一次見到真樹
We went back
我們的身分
to being a prosecutor and a suspect.
又變回檢察官跟嫌疑犯
Please have a seat.
請坐
This morning, lawyer Yuki Umeda turned himself in
梅田祐希律師在今天早上
at Yokohama Minami Police Station.
主動前往橫濱南署作證
He will be asked
未來他會以證人的身分
to come to the police station as a witness,
前往警察署做筆錄
but Yuki Umeda says that he didn't commit the arson.
根據梅田祐希的供述，他並沒有縱火
What?
什麼？
Koichiro Nogi, your father, had promised to refer Umeda for a job.
依梅田所述
Umeda says he went to the Nogi residence because he hadn't received any replies.
然而遲遲沒有下文 於是他在火災當天拜訪野木家
But your father refused to meet Umeda due to having a visitor at the time.
但令尊以有訪客為由婉拒梅田
Were you at the Nogi residence at that time?
當時你人在野木家嗎？
Yes.
你好
Uh, pardon me for disturbing you at night.
那個，不好意思這麼晚來拜訪
My name is Umeda, and I'm a lawyer.
敝姓梅田，是一名律師
Is Mr. Nogi home?
請問野木律師在家嗎？
It's me speaking.
我就是
M-Mr. Nogi? It's me, Umeda.
是野木律師啊？我是梅田
I know this might be rude,
我知道這麼做非常失禮
but could I please speak with you, even for just a little bit?
但能不能占用一點時間談談呢？
It's about a job referral as we discussed before.
是關於之前找工作的事
I'm sorry, but I have company at the moment.
不好意思，我現在有訪客
Then, when would be better?
那請問何時有空？
I will contact you later.
我會再聯絡你
I heard you asked him how to get in touch with me.
聽說你是跟祐希 問到我的聯絡方式，是嗎？
What are you trying to get from him?
你到底想從祐希那打聽什麼？
You didn't even give me a chance to talk to you.
先前我就算想談，你也不理不睬啊
There's nothing I can tell you.
我對你無話可說
Don't pry with stupid questions.
別再進行無意義的調查了
What the hell is this?
這算什麼啊？
Listen to me, Masaki.
聽好了，真樹
Don't stick your nose into this matter anymore.
別再插手這件事了
What do you mean?
什麼意思？
He asked me if I could give him an introduction for a job.
他來是想拜託我介紹工作
Yuki?
祐希嗎？
He asked you?
他來求你？
I plan on finding him a suitable law firm, or rather,
我打算介紹一間與梅田律師相襯
somewhere better than he deserves.
甚至更加理想的事務所
At any rate,
話說回來
you seem to have a lot of odd friends.
你的朋友淨是些怪人呢
Even in their thirties,
都年過三十了
they're all juvenile and naive.
卻都不諳世事且幼稚
You are too.
不管是你
Mr. Umeda is too.
還是梅田律師
So is that prosecutor, Kanade Nishimura.
還有那個西村奏檢座
And that girl Kaori Oikawa.
名為及川香織的女孩也一樣
She even came to my office and--
她居然直接跑到事務所找我…
Don't speak ill of my friends.
不准你說我朋友壞話
Kaori and Kanade
無論是香織還是小奏
just wanted to know…
都是因為你…
about that case of yours.
因為那起事件…
ENVIRONMENTAL ENERGY CORRUPTION CASE
（環境能源貪汙案）
If you weren't involved in that case…
要是沒發生那種事情…
Kaori wouldn't have--
香織就不會出意外…
That's what I mean by juvenile.
所以我才會說幼稚
Losing your friend
朋友過世
was extremely tragic.
這確實令人哀痛
But what does it have to do with me?
但她的去世與我何干？
Calm down and think about it.
你冷靜思考看看
That accident happened
那起意外
because she was being too emotional.
是她一時衝動所引起的
It's not your fault either.
你也一樣
You were only seated beside her.
就只是坐在副駕駛座
Masaki, you need to grow up a little.
真樹，變得成熟點吧
You were the one who was supposed to take over our family.
你本該繼承這個家
But look at you.
但瞧瞧現在的你
When and where did you go wrong to end up like this?
你是走錯哪一步才變成這副德行？
Don't let that voice recorder concern you.
錄音機的事也一樣
I'll say it again.
我再說一次
Don't stick your nose into this any further!
別再插手這件事了！
Whatever you do--
不管你再怎麼…
Shut up!
閉嘴！
I don't have…
我已經…
any time left.
沒剩多少時間了
What do you mean?
什麼意思？
I…
我…
didn't want to become like you.
不想變得跟你一樣
That's all.
僅此而已
Mr. Nogi.
野木先生
Are you listening?
你有在聽嗎？
Okay.
這樣啊
Yuki wasn't the arsonist.
祐希沒有縱火啊
Yuki…
祐希…
didn't do it.
沒幹那種事啊
Good.
那就好
You didn't know this fact,
你完全不知情
and yet you were trying to protect Yuki Umeda?
卻包庇了梅田祐希？
You covered for him
你護著他
and said you did it to an officer patrolling the area,
聲稱是自己做的 被在現場巡邏的員警
and were arrested at the scene.
以現行犯的身分逮捕
Yes.
是的
I'll ask you one more time.
我重新確認一遍
Did you commit arson?
你並沒有縱火？
I didn't.
確實沒有
Then why did you say you did?
那你為什麼要這麼做？
Because I'm an idiot.
因為我太笨了
You should know by now, prosecutor.
你也知道吧？檢座
I'm… pretty stupid.
我就只是一個笨蛋
I'm stupid,
笨歸笨
but at that time,
但是當個笨蛋
it was the most…
對我來說…
important thing for me.
是最重要的事
The interrogation is finished.
今天的訊問就此結束
You will be released tomorrow.
明天將會釋放你
You haven't been completely cleared of the charges.
你的嫌疑並未完全洗清
However,
但是呢
you are seriously ill now.
你現在罹患重病
Your admission to a hospital is the condition of your release.
法院已經決定 要以住院治療為條件釋放你
You must go to the hospital right now.
請你立刻前往醫院
Masaki has been released?
真樹被釋放了嗎？
Was his case dismissed?
意思是不起訴嗎？
He's out, on condition he checks into a hospital.
是以住院治療為條件釋放
But until the real culprit is discovered, the disposition will be pending.
在查出犯人之前算是暫不處分
How is Yuki doing?
祐希還好嗎？
Being summoned by the police so many times is bringing him down.
他被警察傳喚好幾次，為此苦惱
I see.
是喔
I still can't believe
不過真沒想到
Masaki was covering for Yuki.
真樹竟然包庇祐希
Well, most people would lie to cover up their own crimes.
正常來說大家會 為了讓自己脫罪才說謊
Yuki brought it on himself.
祐希也很傻
He went to Mr. Nogi's house uninvited
竟然硬要跑去野木律師家
and was mistaken for an arsonist.
還被人誤認成縱火犯
They're pretty much the same.
真的是半斤八兩
They both did dumb things.
蠢過頭了
What on earth were they thinking?
那兩個人到底在搞什麼啊？
Seriously.
就是說啊
What were they thinking?
到底在做什麼？
As I was saying that, an idea came to mind.
雖然我嘴上是那麼說，心裡卻在想
Maybe Masaki thought
真樹說不定
he should take the blame as a way of making amends.
是為了贖罪才會想替他人承受罪行
He probably felt that he didn't have very long to live
他察覺到自己時日無多
so he shouldtake the blame
所以認為只要自己頂罪
to save Yuki and Tomo.
就能拯救祐希跟小知
In his mind,this was atonement for Kaori who died,
他那麼做是為了死去的香織
and for us who lost our friend.
失去同伴的我們
As well as
以及…
for me and my father.
我和父親，他想藉此贖罪
Kanade, you're the same too.
小奏，你也一樣
What?
什麼？
I mean,
我是指那件事
you suddenly disappeared with Masaki.
你一聲不響，跟真樹搞失蹤
I guess I did some dumb things too.
結果我也跟他們一樣笨
I'm barely hanging on to my job. It's a wonder I'm still a prosecutor.
居然還能苟延殘喘繼續當檢察官 連我都覺得不可思議
Huh?
什麼？
Don't you know, Kanade?
小奏，你還不知道？
Know what?
知道什麼？
Uh,
那個…
Takashi lied for you.
是貴志先生幫你瞞住的喔
When he got a call from the branch chief,
分部長打電話去你家時
he said you were sleeping.
他撒謊說你因病睡著了
He made an excuse for you.
是他幫你蒙混過去的
Isn't that why you didn't get in trouble?
是多虧有他，才能勉強息事寧人吧？
The fish that got away was pretty big, wouldn't you say?
你真的讓一個好男人跑了
I know.
我知道啦
I'll never find anybody as nice as him.
那種好人再也找不到第二個了
I bet most people don't know that prosecutors can be idiots too.
話說世人應該沒想到 有個這麼蠢的檢察官
I'm a young girl after all.
我終究只是個女孩子
I suffer from relationship problems too.
會為喜歡對象的事苦惱
-Wait. -And…
-慢著 -然後…
Did you say "young girl"?
你剛才說自己是“女孩子”？
-No, I didn't. -You did.
-我沒說 -你說了
I did? Really?
我說了？真的？
What? No.
什麼？沒有吧
-You said "young girl." -I said "young girl?"
-你自稱“女孩子” -我說自己是“女孩子”？
I can't believe I said that.
我在說什麼啊？
Me neither.
虧你說得出口
It's been so long
好久沒這樣
since we were able to talk together like this.
跟小知悠哉地聊天了
Yeah.
是啊
Hey. Why don't you sleep over tonight?
我說啊
Are you really asking for that much pampering?
我真的該縱容你？
I guess not.
果然不行？
Do you know I have an unemployed husband being questioned by the police,
我現在有當證人又失業的老公
and a kid?
跟孩子要顧耶
I don't think I can handle looking after you too.
沒辦法照顧小奏
Absolutely not.
說得也是
These are the times I wish Kaori were around.
要是這時候香織在就好了
Three of us could talk.
就能三人一起聊天了
Though we wouldn't have been able to tell her all this.
這種事沒辦法找她談吧
If we had told her, she would have made such a fuss.
要是跟她說一定會鬧得天翻地覆
You're right.
也對喔
But…
不過…
I would have liked to meet a more mature Kaori.
我還是有點想見長大後的香織
Me too.
我也是
MINATO GENERAL HOSPITAL
（橫濱市立港綜合醫院）
Doctor, are you saying
那麼，醫生
I should get surgery right away?
你建議我立刻動手術嗎？
That's my opinion.
我是那麼認為的
What would happen if I don't?
不動手術的話，我會怎麼樣？
The hematemesis from the small intestine was caused by cancer metastasizing.
因十二指腸吐血，表示癌細胞擴散了
Besides the small intestine,
除了十二指腸外
we can see it spreading to the bile duct and part of the liver.
還擴散到膽管跟肝臟的一部分
Surgically removing it
我想建議你
is the best option.
進行外科切除手術
Without surgery,
不動手術
will I die?
我會死嗎？
It's not certain,
我無法肯定
but if you don't do anything, it is a high probability.
但是不做任何處置，那就很有可能
Doctor,
醫生
can I ask you something?
我能問個問題嗎？
What is it?
想問什麼？
Why are you trying
你為何試圖救我？
I'm the guy
畢竟我曾經
who ran away… with your fiancée.
跟你的未婚妻一起逃走
Why extend help to someone like me?
像我這種人渣 你只要扔在一旁不管就好了啊
That fact…
那件事…
and the fact that you're my patient…
跟野木先生是我負責的病人
are not connected.
兩者並不相關
As a doctor,
我身為醫生
I prioritize treating you.
必須以治療你為第一優先
I see.
這樣啊
And you operating on me…
要動手術的意思是…
means you'll have my life in your hands.
我的命會交到你的手上？
That's true.
沒錯
Your life
野木先生的性命
would be in my hands.
屆時會交到我手上
So…
我…
I can let you…
可以讓你活下去
live or die.
也能殺了你
According to the police,
根據警察的報告
Yuki Umeda is still denying that he set the fire.
梅田祐希至今仍否認縱火
Didn't Umeda see anybody who might be the actual culprit?
他沒有目擊到疑似嫌犯的人物嗎？
No, he's saying he didn't see anybody suspicious.
他說不記得有看到可疑人士
The Nogi residence was already in flames when he noticed it.
當他回過神來，野木家已經起火了
Masaki Nogi also denied setting the fire.
野木真樹也否認縱火
Yes.
是的
Masaki Nogi once testified that he spread gasoline around, right?
野木真樹曾說過 自己潑灑了汽油，對吧？
Yes, but that seems to be a lie he made up to cover for Yuki Umeda.
對，但那是他為了包庇梅田祐希 臨時編出的謊言
That means both Masaki Nogi and Yuki Umeda are almost certainly innocent.
代表野木真樹跟梅田祐希的嫌疑 雖然接近清白，卻尚未洗清
Yes.
沒錯
There are no clues about the real arsonist.
沒有其他犯人的線索
I guess we're back to square one.
結果又回到原點了
Come in.
進來
Excuse me.
打擾了
Branch chief, Ms. Nishimura.
分部長、西村檢座
They are allowing visitors to see Koichiro Nogi.
野木浩一郎能會客了
I'll go talk to him.
我去找他問話
Are you here to see Mr. Nogi?
請問是要見野木先生嗎？
Oh, yes.
呃，是的
Those flowers are lovely.
那些花真美
He's been receiving many bouquets since moving to this room.
自從他搬進這間病房後就收到好幾次
Who is it from?
是誰送的？
We don't know. There is no name attached.
不知道耶，沒有留下姓名
I'm coming in.
我進去囉
Mr. Nogi, you've got flowers again.
野木先生，又有人送花來了
Thank you.
謝謝你
Pardon me, sir.
打擾了
Masaki has been released?
真樹被釋放了？
Yes.
是的
It's clear that he covered for Yuki Umeda whom he ran into at the scene.
我們發現他是為了包庇 當天出現在失火現場的梅田祐希
Masaki was only saying he did it to protect him.
才堅稱是自己犯案
Mr. Umeda set the fire?
是梅田律師縱火？
No, he probably didn't do it either.
不，應該也不是
Mr. Nogi.
野木律師
I'm sorry to be questioning you while you're just recovering,
雖然你的身體才剛好轉 我不好意思追問
but I need to ask you one thing.
但必須請教一個問題
Mr. Nogi,
野木律師
do you have any idea who set the fire?
你對那個縱火犯有什麼頭緒嗎？
We're speculating
我想那位犯人
that the culprit brought a plastic fuel can to the garage area,
是拿裝有汽油的塑膠桶進入車庫
spread gasoline around, and lit it on fire.
並潑灑汽油縱火
This was a vicious crime
府上徹底燒毀了
that burned your house down completely and might have taken your life.
你也險些送命 顯然是有人心懷惡意，故意犯罪
Can you think of anybody who holds a grudge against you?
有誰對你懷恨在心嗎？
Someone who holds a grudge against me?
對我懷恨在心的人？
Yes.
是的
There are so many people.
多不勝數啊
Only fate knows which one.
我完全想不到會是誰
Although in my mind, I was prepared
我預料到總有一天會演變成這樣
for something like this to happen.
所以早就做好覺悟了
I see.
我明白了
If you think of anything or remember anything, please call us.
若你發現任何疑點 或想起什麼事，麻煩通知我
I'll come here again.
我會再次拜訪的
Please take care.
請保重身體
Kanade.
奏小姐
Yes.
是
Is Masaki sick?
真樹生病了嗎？
So, that's why
所以…
he came to see me?
他才出現在我面前？
I think so.
應該是那樣沒錯
He probably wanted to have a sense of closure
我認為他是想要
about various things in the past.
為過去的種種做個了結
He tried…
他打算…
in his own way.
透過自己的方式劃下句點
So you were the first person who saw the fire and reported it?
你是第一個發現火災並報警的人？
Yes. I made a delivery to a home close to where the fire broke out.
對，我到發生火災的那個家附近送貨
On the way back,
在回程途中
I noticed the flames and hurried to call 119 for an emergency.
發現失火，才慌慌張張地打了119
What time was that?
那是幾點的事？
I already informed the detective the other day,
前陣子我才跟刑警說
but about ten at night.
是晚上十點左右
I already submitted the photos of the sales slip
我應該有提出當時的單據
This must be it.
就是這張
That night,
當天晚上
did you see anybody suspicious near the Nogi residence?
你有在野木家周遭看到可疑人士嗎？
How can I tell if somebody's suspicious or not?
我哪知道哪個人可疑
Does that mean you remember anyone passing by?
意思是你跟好幾個人擦身而過？
I don't remember.
不記得了啦
People came out to see. That's it.
是有人發現火災就衝出家門啦
Did you talk to them?
你有跟對方談話嗎？
Enough! Why do I have to answer the same questions over and over?
你有完沒完啊？一直問同樣的問題
You're making me miss work!
這樣我是要怎麼工作啊？
Please calm down.
請你冷靜點
Why are you telling me to calm down?
你這樣講不對吧？
I had nothing to do with the fire.
叫我冷靜？搞得好像我有毛病一樣
Could you please look at this?
能請你看看這張照片嗎？
-Photo of a contactless delivery. -Yes.
-這是把貨物放在門口的證明照片 -是的
The reflection in the window.
玻璃窗戶的這個地方
Here.
這邊
Doesn’t it look like a human face?
不覺得像是人臉嗎？
And this red portion.
然後這個紅色的部分
Possibly a plastic fuel can?
像是塑膠桶對吧？
I think it could be.
是有一點像
Please get this image analyzed.
麻煩你分析了
Yes.
好的
This is Nishimura.
我是西村
Oh, the face is visible now?
什麼？知道是誰的臉了？
Yes, we got the face to be discernable somehow.
對，勉強辨別出長相了
No results came up in our criminal records database.
不過對方不在 警方的犯罪記錄資料庫中
But…
但是呢
the item visible from the bag
他身後那東西
was indeed a fuel can.
確認是塑膠桶沒錯
Good news, but still, the identity of the man is unknown.
真是好消息 不過現在還不清楚那男人的身分
Unfortunately.
很遺憾
Anyway, I'll send the image to you.
總之我先把照片傳給你
Yes.
好的
FOLLOW-UP TO YOUR REQUEST
（關於你吩咐的那件事）
You're right. It's hard to determine the culprit from just this.
光靠這個的確很難認出犯人
His clothes aren't distinctive either.
服裝也不具特徵
We will conduct interviews again based on this photo.
我會拿這張照片再次進行問話
Yes, please do so.
好，拜託你了
We must find out something.
我得想點辦法
That photo is the only clue we have so far.
現階段那張照片就是唯一的線索
I'm here to get my stuff.
我回去拿行李
Okay.
是喔
I'm sorry.
對不起
I caused you so much trouble.
我給你添了很多麻煩
Not just that…
不僅如此…
but for everything.
真的很抱歉
I'll probably be operating on him when the surgery is scheduled.
若他決定動手術
Did he agree to it?
他要動手術啊？
He still seems to be unsure.
他本人似乎還沒決定
What he needs now is the will to live.
他現在最需要的是求生意志
He needs to have hope
以及在未來
for whatever future he will have.
讓他活下去的希望
How are you doing?
你還好嗎？
I…
我…
I can't even tell if I'm keeping a cool head like you, Takashi.
不確定自己有沒有像貴志那樣冷靜
I'm not really cool-headed.
我哪裡冷靜了？
I'm just trying to hold myself together as a physician.
只是希望能保有身為醫生的自我
It's actually a struggle.
其實我根本沒有餘裕
So Kanade,
所以小奏
you shouldn't give up your job of being a prosecutor.
你也要貫徹檢察官的工作
I know how hard you've worked
當年你是從絕望的谷底
to become one
努力往上爬
after hitting rock bottom.
最終才當上檢察官
NOTIFICATION OF REJECTION
（不合格通知單）
What's the matter?
你怎麼了？
It's because you were there for me.
那都是因為有貴志在
It's just hot water, but it will warm you.
只是杯熱開水，不過喝了會暖和些
This is good.
真好喝
Oh, so you passed it. The bar exam.
是喔，你通過司法考試了啊？
Yes.
對
Your efforts paid off.
那是憑你自己的努力
In the end,
我到頭來啊
I couldn't do anything.
什麼都無法為你做
I don't remember much of what happened after that.
之後的事我不太記得了
It was morning before I knew it.
一回過神，就到了早上
I heard people cheering banzai on TV.
電視中傳來了萬歲的歡呼聲
-Banzai!
-萬歲！
In the recent presidential election of the Democratic Liberal Party,
前陣子舉辦的民事黨總裁選舉
Lower House member Shotaro Azuma was elected party president.
最後由東正太郎眾議院議員當選總裁
He is the elder son of former prime minister Tadao Azuma.
東議員是東忠男前總理大臣的長子
If Mr. Azuma becomes the prime minister,
若他就任總理大臣
he would be Japan's second-ever second-generation prime minister.
就成了有史以來 第二組擔任總理大臣的父子
Mr. Azuma visited his constituents for the first time since being elected…
東議員當上總裁後 首度回到當地選區…
Shotaro Azuma.
東正太郎
He was accused of bribery
他是20年前
in the environmental energy corruption case 20 years ago.
父親負責的環境能源貪汙案中
My father was in charge of the case.
有收賄罪嫌疑的政治家
That same man is now about to become prime minister.
而那個人在角逐下任的總理大臣之位
I have been proceeding with great effort--
至今致力於種種…
-Not guilty. -In the end,
-被告無罪 -結果到最後
diet member Azuma was found not guilty.
東議員被判無罪
And my father…
而我父親…
Diet member Shotaro Azuma takes the office of party president
東正太郎議員在東京都內
Mr. Azuma will be leading the country in the future, and--
東議員將成為國家的舵手 他今後的…
Those flowers are lovely.
那些花真美
He's been receiving many bouquets since moving to this room.
自從他搬進這間病房後就收到好幾次
SHOTARO AZUMA INAUGURAL PRESS CONFERENCE
（東正太郎在選區報告就任新總裁）
That man!
這個男人！
NATIONAL DIET HANDBOOK
（《國會手冊》）
OFFICIAL SITE
（官網）
That man was the secretary of Shotaro Azuma's father,
那個男人是東正太郎的父親
Tadao Azuma, who was a former prime minister.
前總理大臣東忠男的祕書
SECRETARY YOJI AKIBA
（秋葉洋二祕書）
Shall we talk outside? We should leave this place.
我們離開這裡好嗎？ 我們換個地點談吧
Where are you going?
你要去哪啊？
Who are you calling?
你正打給誰？
SHOTARO AZUMA'S INAUGURAL PRESS CONFERENCE
（東正太郎在選區報告就任新總裁）
Excuse me.
打擾了
…for a better Japan.
只想讓國家變得更好
I have been proceeding with great effort…
於是我付出努力…
Thanks to all your generous support,
全都多虧了大家的支持
I was able to become--
我才有辦法走到…
What do you want?
有什麼事嗎？
Mr. Nogi.
野木律師
That case my father was involved in and the arson.
我父親被捲入的那起事件 和這次的縱火案
Aren't they connected in some way?
其實有所關連？
Not only that,
不僅如此
but Kaori's accident
香織那起意外事故
and Masaki's disappearance as well.
跟真樹失蹤，其實全都有關吧？
Please tell me
請告訴我真相
Subtitle translation by: Ikuko Sachs
字幕翻譯：蔡柏頤
That man tried to kill you.
這個男人想要你的命
Everything was concocted by him.
一切都是某個男人安排的
I don't remember.
我不記得了
Were you convinced by it, Kanade?
那樣小奏能接受嗎？
I only fulfilled my duty.
只是貫徹了使命
That's the real battle.
那才是真正要分出勝負的時候
I shouldn't turn around.
不能回頭
We were never destined to meet.
一切都是命運 打從一開始我們就不該遇見